DOESN'T ANYBODY EVER GO HOME?
大伙都没回家?
YOU'RE HERE.
你也是啊
EXACTLY.
没错
TRUST ME, YOU DON'T WANT TO MODEL
相信我 你们不会愿意
YOUR SOCIAL LIFE AROUND MINE.
把我的社交生活树立成你们的样板的
IF IT MAKES YOU FEEL ANY BETTER,
如果这能让你好过点的话
HOTCH AND MORGAN TOOK OFF.
HOTCH跟MORGAN来吧
HOTCH IS MARRIED, MORGAN'S, YOU KNOW, MORGAN.
HOTCH已婚  MORGAN的吧 你晓得他自己一套
WHAT'S THIS?
这是什么?
POLICE IN DAYTON, OHIO
OHIO州DAYTON郡的警察
NEED OUR HELP WITH A SERIAL RAPIST.
需要我们帮忙分析一个连环强奸犯
WHAT'S THE STORY?
发生什么事了?
3 MONTHS AGO HE RAPED 4 STUDENTS
三个月前他强奸了五个
AT A SMALL BIBLE COLLEGE.
某小型神学院的学生
ROUGHLY, AN ATTACK A WEEK, THEN SUDDENLY NOTHING,
大概 一星期一宗 然后就突然停止了作案
UNTIL 9 DAYS AGO WHEN HE SUDDENLY REAPPEARED
直到9天前他又突然出现了
WITH A WHOLE NEW VICTIM PATTERN.
使用了全新的作案手法
BOTH THOSE WOMEN ARE IN THEIR 30s.
那些受害女人都30岁左右
THEY WERE RAPED ABOUT 5 DAYS APART.
她们分别在大约五天内被强奸了
WHERE HAVE THE NEW ATTACKS TAN PLACE?
新案件的发案地点在哪?
OPPOSITE ENDS OF THE CITY.
城市的不同边缘
HE WAS WAITING FOR THEM WHEN THEY GOT HOME.
他等着在她们回家时下手
HOW DO WE KNOW IT'S THE SAME GUY?
怎么判定是同个人作案呢?
HE LEAVES VOICE MAILS FOR THEM.
他留了口信给她们
FREEZING THEM WITH FEAR BEFORE THEY EVEN SEE HIM.
让她们在看到他之前先被震慑住
THEY DON'T RECOGNIZE THE VOICE?
她们认不出声音来吗?
NO.
不行
COPS EVEN HAVE DNA, BUT IT'S JUST NOT IN THE SYSTEM.
警方拿到了DNA 可是在比对系统里找不到
WHY WOULD SOMEONE ATTACKING COLLEGE STUDENTS SUDDENLY WIDEN HIS NET?
为什么袭击在校学生的人会突然广撒网了呢?
SERIAL RAPISTS HARDLY EVER CHANGE VICTIMOLOGY ONCE IT'S ESTABLISHED.
连环强奸犯很少改变他固定的被害者模式
IT'S BASED ON A FANTASY THAT'S VERY SPECIFIC.
这都基于非常特殊的幻想
MAYBE HE'S TELLING THESE WOMEN THAT NO ONE'S SAFE.
或许他想告诉受害者 人人都有危险吧
CALL HOTCH AND MORGAN.
打电话给HOTCH和MORGAN
TELL THEM WE'RE UP AS SOON AS WE'RE CLEARED FOR TAKEOFF.
告诉他们我们一确定接手就马上动身
YES, SIR.
得令
WELL, THANKS.
到了 谢谢
Man: I THINK WERE READY TO MEET.
我想我们就要见面了
TRUST ME.
相信我啦
I KNOW WHAT YOU WANT.
我知道你要什么
YOU CAME HOME EARLY TONIGHT.
今晚你回来得早啊
AAH! NO! NO!
啊! 不! 不!
YOU TEND TO FORGET, DON'T YOU?
你都快忘了吧?
WHAT?
什么呀?
ALL THE DIFFERENT MOODS ON THE PLANE.
飞机上所有的不同情绪
I THINK THE MINDSET'S DIFFERENT
我想因为这些受害者活着
WHEN THE VICTIMS ARE STILL ALIVE.
我们的情绪就有所不同
OK, WE GOT NEW INFORMATION ON LAST NIGHT'S VICTIM.
从昨晚的受害者那里得到了些信息
ALICIA JORDAN, 38.
ALICIA JORDAN 38岁
M.O. IS THE SAME.
作案手法相同
HE WAS WAITING FOR HER TO GET HOME,
他等着她到家
HE BROKE IN THROUGH THE BACK, SUBDUED HER WITH A GUN.
他从后门闯进去 用枪指吓她
ANSWERING MACHINE?
电话留言机呢?
LEFT A MESSAGE ABOUT AN HOUR OR SO BEFORE.
在大约一小时前留了条口信
I CAN'T IMAGINE BEING TAUNTED LIKE THAT IN MY OWN HOUSE, YOU KNOW?
我真不敢想象在自己家里会受到那样的嘲弄
WELL, THE MESSAGES AREN'T TAUNTS...
那些留言可不是嘲弄
THEY'RE OVERTURES.
它们是序幕
I THINK WE'RE READY, TRUST ME.
我觉得我们准备好了
HE'S BEING SINCERE.
相信我 他要动真格的了
SOUNDS LIKE WE'RE DEALING WITH A POWER REASSURANCE RAPIST.
听起来我们象是在处理 一个权利重认型强奸犯
TO HIM THE MESSAGES ARE COURTSHIPS.
对他来说那些留言是在求爱
HE'S INTRODUCING HIMSELF TO THE VICTIMS.
他把自己介绍给受害者
IF THAT'S THE CASE, HE MUST'VE STALKED THEM
这种情况的话 他应该是盯着她们
TO KNOW SO MUCH ABOUT THEIR LIVES.
以便深入了解她们的生活
FIRST VICTIMS WERE ALL COLLEGE STUDENTS, ALL RELIGIOUS.
第一批受害者都是在校学生 都是信徒
WHY CHANGE?
怎么会变呢?
HAVE THE POLICE FOUND ANY CONNECTION BETWEEN THE LATEST VICTIMS?
警察找到最后那些受害者的关联了吗?
NO, NOTHING YET.
一无所获
WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT WHAT MADE HIM GO OFF SCRIPT.
我们得找出什么让他偏离了原来的模式
MAGGIE CALLAHAN, I'M THE DETECTIVE ON THIS JOB.
MAGGIE CALLAHAN 我是本案的侦探
HEY, JASON GIDEON, HOW ARE YOU?
JASON GIDEON 你好
AARON HOTCHNER.
AARON HOTCHNER
AS SOON AS HE CHANGED VICTIMS
他一改了受害者
I KNEW I COULD USE YOUR HELP.
我就知道你们能帮上忙
YOUR THOUGHTS?
你有什么见解?
SERIAL RAPIST USUALLY HAVE A SET FANTASY,
连环强奸犯一般都有固定的幻想
I FIGURED IF WE CAN GET A HANDLE ON WHAT MADE HIM CHANGE,
我断定只要能弄清楚是什么让他转变的
IT WOULD GIVE US OUR BEST SHOT AT NAILING THIS GUY.
就能尽快抓住这家伙
IS THERE A PLACE WHERE OUR TEAM COULD SET UP?
有地方让我们小组开工么?
YOU GOT IT. IN THE CONFERENCE ROOM.
准备好了 在案件讨论室
THANK YOU.
谢了
AGENT GIDEON, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TALK TO A LOT OF VICTIMS.
GIDEON探员 你们去跟大批受害者谈话时
IT WOULD BE HELPFUL TO HAVE AN EXTRA FEMALE PRESENCE.
多个女性在场会有帮助的
CAN YOU PROMISE ME YOU'LL BE SENSITIVE?
你能答应表现得机灵点么?
AS LONG AS YOU PROMISE ME TO STAY PISSED OFF AT WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM.
只要可以让我查出在她们身上发生的悲剧
I'VE BEEN ON THIS CASE SINCE DAY ONE.
我第一天就介入了案件
I DON'T WANT TO HAVE TO STEP ASIDE.
我可不想置身事外
YOU WILL NOT HAVE TO.
你也不用这么做
THANK YOU.
谢谢
CAN YOU ROLL OVER TO YOUR OTHER SIDE PLEASE?
请转个身好吗?
PULL YOUR GOWN DOWN JUST A LITTLE--
拉下你的睡袍 就一会
EXCUSE US, PLEASE.
请让让
WE'RE FROM THE FBI.
我们是FBI
I REALIZE YOU'VE ALREADY SPOKEN TO THE POLICE,
我知道你已经跟警方谈过了
BUT WE WERE HOPING YOU--
不过我们希望你
A FEW QUESTIONS YOU COULD ANSWER FOR US.
你能回答我们些问题
YEAH. EVERY TIME I THINK IT'S OVER
好的 我一以为没事了
SOMEONE ELSE WANTS TO PHOTOGRAPH ME
就有人想来给我拍照
OR TOUCH ME OR ASK ME TO RELIVE IT.
或是来碰触我 或是让我再体验一次
WE WILL KEEP THIS SHORT, I PROMISE.
我保证我们会很快的
WHEN THE ATTACKS FIRST STARTED,
当袭击第一次开始时
THEY PUT GUARDS ON ALL THE CAMPUS GATES ON CAMPUS.
警卫就被安排在了校园的每个校门
BUT THAT MAN STILL SOMEHOW GOT IN THE DORM ROOMS.
但那家伙还是不知怎么就进了宿舍
HAD YOU NOTICED ANYONE NEW ON CAMPUS?
你留意那些校园的新面孔了么?
WE'VE ALREADY TALKED ABOUT THIS.
这问题我们谈过了
I KNOW IT'S HARD,
我知道这很痛苦
BUT SOMETIMES IT HELPS TO GO THROUGH IT.
但有时它能帮助解决问题
MAYBE SOMEBODY QUIET,
有没有个人不大说话
WHO SEEMED LIKE HE WAS ALWAYS JUST A LITTLE TOO CLOSE.
看起来又很亲切
I DON'T THINK SO.
我不认识这样的人
WHAT ABOUT ANYONE THAT'S SUDDENLY NOT AROUND ANYMORE?
有没有突然间消失的人呢?
BEFORE THAT MAN DID WHAT HE DID
那家伙在作案前
HE TOLD ME I SHOULD GET A DOG FOR PROTECTION.
告诉我该养条狗防身
AND THEN HE SAID OR MAYBE YOU CAN LET
然后他说或许你该让
YOUR PARENTS HAVE DEXTER STAY WITH YOU.
你父母找个吉祥物给你
YOU SAID THAT YOUR ATTACKER KNEW THE THINGS
你说袭击你的人知道你心里想的
THAT YOU THOUGHT. WHAT DID YOU MEAN BY THAT?
这是什么意思呢?
HE SAID THAT WE WEREN'T THE TYPE OF PEOPLE TO JUST STAY
他说我们不是那种
INSIDE AND READ BOOKS,
只会呆在家看看书的人
AND HE TALKED ABOUT TAKING ME AWAY TO POSITANO, ITALY,
他还谈到要带我去意大利的POSITANO
AND DRINKING WHITE WINE AND LISTENING TO AL GREEN.
然后喝白葡萄酒 听着AL GREEN的歌
IS THERE ANY SIGNIFICANCE TO THAT?
那些都有什么含义么?
MY FAVORITE PLACE IN THE WORLD,
世界上我最喜爱的地方
THE ONLY ALCOHOL I DRINK, AND MY FAVORITE SINGER.
我唯一会喝的酒 还有我最喜爱的歌手
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW HE CAN KNOW ANY OF IT.
我真不明白他是怎么知道的
ANY MALES IN YOUR LIFE THAT YOU MAY HAVE TOLD ABOUT THE FAMILY DOG?
你有没有跟身边的男性谈起过家里养的狗?
I DON'T HAVE ANY EXPERIENCE WITH BOYS.
我都没有跟男孩子接触的经验
THERE'S NO ONE I WOULD'VE TOLD.
我没告诉过任何人
YOU NEED A SECOND?
你再想想?
IT'S HARD TO FOCUS SOMETIMES.
锁定某个时刻是很难的
I KNOW.
我晓得
THE POLICE ALL ACT LIKE JUST BECAUSE HE DIDN'T KILL YOU,
警察的行动都好像是在说 他不知何故没有杀你
HE DIDN'T SOMEHOW END YOUR LIFE.
他不知如何结束你的生命
DID YOU TAKE MY ADVICE AND TALK TO SOMEONE?
你听我的建议去跟谁聊过了吗?
THERE'S ALWAYS A PRIEST AVAILABLE ON CAMPUS.
校园里一直都有可告解的牧师
I MEAN, A WOMAN.
我意思是 女的
I DON'T KNOW. MAYBE THAT WOULD BE GOOD.
我不晓得 或许会有好处
SO MANY LIVES HAVE BEEN RUINED HERE.
那么多的生命都在这毁了
WHEN I WENT TO THE DOCTOR...
我去看医生的时候
HE SAID THAT MY INJURIES WERE MINOR.
他说我的外伤不严重
AND YOU THINK IF THEY WERE SOMEHOW WORSE, IT WOULD BE BETTER?
你认为如果外伤严重的话你会好受点?
I DON'T KNOW.
我不知道
LOOK AT ME.
看着我
SOMEONE HANDS OVER A WALLET AT GUNPOINT,
有人在被枪指着时双手奉上了钱包
EVERYONE THINKS THAT'S THE BEST THING TO DO.
所有人都认为这是最明智的做法
YOU DID WHAT YOU HAD TO DO TO SURVIVE.
你做了为争取生存该做的事
DON'T LET ANYONE TELL YOU DIFFERENT.
不要听别人不同的说法
ALL RIGHT?
好吗?
IT'S OK.
没事了
I'M SORRY, BUT I'M GONNA HAVE TO ASK YOU TO LISTEN
对不起 但我还是得让你听听这个
TO THIS AND TELL ME IF THE MAN'S ATTITUDE
然后告诉我这家伙说话的方式
SOUNDS THE SAME AS WHEN HE WAS IN YOUR HOUSE.
听起来跟他在你家时是否一样
Man: I THINK WE'RE READY TO MEET.
我想我们就要见面了
TRUST ME.
相信我
I KNOW WHAT YOU WANT.
我知道你想要什么
HE SOUNDED DIFFERENT.
他听起来不一样
HOW SO?
怎么个不一样?
MORE NERVOUS...
更紧张
EVEN THOUGH HE HAD A GUN.
即使他有枪在手
IT WAS LIKE HE WAS AFRAID TO TALK.
他还是很害怕开口
THANK YOU.
谢谢了
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MATTER HOW HE SOUNDED?
研究他说话的声音有什么用呢?
ON THE PHONE HE CAN REHEARSE,
电话里他可以先排练
AND IN THE FLESH HE CAN'T HIDE HIS TRUE SELF.
在即时情况下他没办法掩藏真我
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
我听不懂
IN HIS DELUSION, THE MAN THINKS OF THESE ATTACKS AS DATES.
在他的错觉里 那家伙把袭击当作是约会
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING TO MAKE HIM THINK THAT.
我可没做什么让他觉得是在约会
WE KNOW YOU DIDN'T.
我们知道你没做什么
THIS IS ENOUGH.
这里可以了
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
非常感谢
EVERYBODY GET SOME SLEEP. WE'VE GOT A BIG DAY TOMORROW.
大家都睡一下吧 明天可是个大日子啊
WHAT'S UP?
怎么啦?
I THINK I LEFT MY GLASSES IN THE CAR.
我想我把眼镜落车上了
I'LL KEEP YOU COMPANY.
我陪你去吧
NO, IT'S ALL RIGHT. WE GOT TO GET TO SLEEP.
不用了 我们该去睡觉了
BE RIGHT THERE.
来了
I FIGURED YOU WOULDN'T BE SLEEPING EITHER.
我就知道你也睡不着
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
你来这里干什么?
I TOOK A ROOM ON THE HALL.
我在大堂开了个房
YOU LIVE 4 BLOCKS AWAY.
你家离这里只有4个街区
EXACTLY.
没错
WHY BE SEPARATED FROM THE WORK?
干吗要跟工作分开呢?
YOU STOLE THE BATHROBE?
你偷了浴衣?
COMPLIMENTARY.
免费赠送的
I CAN'T GET SOMETHING OUT OF MY HEAD.
我脑海里老驱不散些东西
CHERYL ON CAMPUS TODAY,
CHERYL今天在学校里说
SHE SAID SO MANY LIVES HERE HAVE BEEN RUINED.
那么多生命在这里被毁了
YEAH?
是吗?
ONLY 20% OF RAPES ARE EVEN REPORTED.
只有20%的强奸受害者会报案
YOU THINK THERE ARE MORE VICTIMS OUT THERE?
你认为应该有更多的受害者吗?
YOU FIGURE A CATHOLIC SCHOOL,
在一个天主教学校里
THE PERCENTAGES ARE BOUND TO HOLD.
这个比例还算保守估计
UNSUB'S COMMITTED A RAPE THAT NEVER GOT REPORTED.
也许疑犯所犯的罪行还有没被报案的
SOMETHING MADE HIM CHANGE VICTIMS.
有些东西让他改了受害对象
MAYBE HE ALMOST GOT CAUGHT.
或许他几乎被抓住了
MAYBE HE'S RELIGIOUS AND FELT GUILTY.
或许他是修道士 有了罪恶感
MAYBE A VICTIM REMINDED HIM OF HIS SISTER.
或许有个受害者让他想起了他姐姐
SOMETHING.
或是别的什么
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
你怎么想的?
I THINK YOU GOT GOOD INSTINCTS.
我想你有很好的本能
HEY.
嘿
HI.
嗨
ARE YOU OK?
你没事吧?
YEAH, WHY WOULDN'T I BE?
是啊 为什么会有事呢?
NO, REALLY, COME RIGHT IN.
不 说真的 那就进来吧
YOU WANT TO CHECK MY I.D.?
你查我底细来了?
I THOUGHT MAYBE...
我想或许
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TALK.
你需要谈谈
DON'T GO ALL PROFILER ON ME.
不要给我来侧写这套
ELLE, YOU GOT SHOT IN YOUR OWN HOME,
ELLE 你在自己家中了枪
AND THEN YOU CAME BACK TO THE BAU LIKE NOTHING EVEN HAPPENED,
然后若无其事地回到了行为分析科
THINKING YOU MIGHT WANT TO TALK ISN'T PROFILING YOU.
我以为你需要谈谈 可不是侧写你哟
IT'S PSYCH 101.
这是心理障碍101号
PLEASE?
说说吧
AFTER HE SHOT ME.
他开枪打了我后
HE REACHED INTO MY WOUND
他用手插进我的伤口
SO HE COULD WRITE ON THE WALL IN MY BLOOD.
用我的血在墙上写字
I WAS BARELY CONSCIOUS,
我几乎没有知觉
BUT I COULD FEEL HIS HAND IN THERE...
但我能感觉到他的手在那里
AND SOMETIMES IT'S LIKE I CAN STILL FEEL IT.
现在有时候我还能感觉到
ELLE...
ELLE
HE'S DEAD.
他死了
YOU'RE...YOU'RE RIGHT HERE.
你 你活生生的在这呢
YOU WON.
你赢了
GOOD MORNING.
早上好
THANKS FOR COMING IN A LITE EARLY.
谢谢来得这么早
GOOD MORNING. LOUSY COFFEE'S UP.
早上好     "上等"咖啡来了
WE JUST WANT YOU TO HEAR WHAT THE FBI HAS GATHERED
我们要你听听FBI收集到了什么
AND GET YOU ON THE STREETS.
然后让你到外边干活去
SO THE GUY WE'RE LOOKING FOR
我们要找的家伙
IS A CLASSIC POWER REASSURANCE RAPIST.
是个典型的权利重认型强奸犯
THIS DIFFERS FROM A POWER ASSERTIVE RAPIST
不同于那些试图羞辱和伤害受害者的
WHO ATTEMPTS TO HUMILIATE AND TRAUMATIZE HIS VICTIMS,
权力擅断型强奸犯
AS WELL AS THE ANGER RETALIATORY RAPIST
也不同于报复型强奸犯
AND A SEXUAL SADIST,
或者是性虐待狂
WHOSE ATTACKS ARE ALSO RANDOM AND EXCESSIVELY BRUTAL.
这两类罪犯的袭击比较随意 手段比较残酷
THE REASON THAT'S IMPORTANT FOR YOU
你们该知道的重要原因是
TO KNOW--HE'S THE ONLY KIND OF RAPIST
他是唯一一种会选择
WHO TARGETS A SPECIFIC VICTIM.
特定目标当受害者的强奸犯
HE FANTASIZES THAT HE'S IN A RELATIONSHIP WITH THESE WOMEN.
他幻想他跟这些女人有亲密关系
NOW, HE DOESN'T COME ACROSS THEM BY ACCIDENT.
他不是突然跟她们有关系的
THIS IS SOMEONE WITH ACCESS.
他是慢慢接近的
HE'S THE CABLE GUY, OR THE LOCKSMITH...
他可能是电线工或修锁工
HE'S THE GUY WHO READS THE GAS METER.
可能是煤气抄表员
HE CAN DESCRIBE EXACTLY WHAT THESE WOMEN WEAR AND HOW THEY SMELL.
他能叙述那些女人确切的穿着跟体味
THESE DETAILS ARE WHAT FEEDS HIS FANTASY.
这些细节满足了他的幻想
NOW, WE NEED YOU TO LOOK FOR THE OVERLAP BETWEEN THE SETS OF VICTIMS.
我们需要你们去寻找那批受害者的共通点
DELIVERY MEN, LA CREW, HANDYMEN--
投递员 工人 勤杂员
DID THE SCHOOL SHARE WORKERS WITH ANY OF THE RECENT VICTIMS?
最近的受害者周围有学校分配的工人么?
BECAUSE HE SEES THESE AS RELATIONSHIPS,
由于他把这些看做是亲密关系
HE MOST LIKELY LIVES ALONE.
他很可能是独居
AND LIVING ALONE ALLOWS HIM TO INDULGE HIS DELUSION
而且允许他纵容他的错觉
THAT HE'S IN A RELATIONSHIP WITH THESE WOMEN.
即他跟那些女人有着亲密关系
BECAUSE OF THE DISCREPANCY IN THE VICTIMS' AGES.
由于这些受害者的年龄差异
WE CAN ONLY PINPOINT HIS AGE
我们只能确定他的年龄
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN 20 AND 40 YEARS OLD.
在20到40岁之间
IT'S POSSIBLE THAT HE HAS A PROFESSION THAT HE FINDS EMASCULATING,
他很有可能拥有一份看起来很懦弱的职业
SO LOOK FOR SOMEONE IN THEIR LIVES
一份偏离正常性角色的工作
WITH A JOB THAT DEVIATES FROM NORMAL GENDER ROLES,
让他可以在日常生活中寻找猎物
SOMETHING LIKE A SECRETARY.
比如秘书
WE'RE SURE THAT THERE IS SOME OVERLAP.
我们确信这就是共通点
THIS GUY IS A SHADOW AT THE EDGES OF EACH OF THESE WOMEN'S LIVES.
这家伙是游走在那些女人生活边缘的影子
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S SQUARE ONE.
好了 这是第一步
RECANVAS AND BE SURE TO RELAY INFORMATION ON SHIFT CHANGE.
回去反复研究 在换班时做到信息传达
THANKS VERY MUCH.
谢谢大家
I LOOKED INTO THE IDEA OF RAPES
根据你的疑问
THAT WENT UNREPORTED LIKE YOU ASKED.
我调查了是否还有人没有报案
AND?
然后?
2 MONTHS AGO, A FEMALE STUDENT
两个月前 有个女学生
AT HOLY TRINITY COMMITTED SUICIDE.
在三一主日那天自杀了
SHE WASN'T ONE OF THE REPORTED VICTIMS,
她不在有报案的受害者之列
BUT HER SUICIDE REPORT CORRESPONDS ALMOST EXACTLY
但她的自杀报告几乎吻合
TO WHEN THE CAMPUS ATTACKS STOPPED.
校园袭击停止的时间
MAYBE THERE ARE MORE VICTIMS OUT THERE.
也许还有更多未知的受害者
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW OUR DAUGHTER'S DEATH IS FBI BUSINESS.
我不明白我们女儿的死亡关FBI什么事
WE'RE INVESTIGATING A SERIES OF SEXUAL ASSAULTS
我们在调查一系列发生在
THAT TOOK PLACE ON SHELLY'S CAMPUS.
SHELLY学校里的性攻击
WERE YOU AWARE OF THE ATTACKS?
你知道这些攻击吗?
OF COURSE. IT WAS HORRIBLE.
当然知道 很恐怖的
THERE'S NO GOOD WAY TO SAY THIS, SO I'M JUST GOING TO ASK.
没有婉转的方法说这些 那我就直接问了
IS IT POSSIBLE THE SHELLY WAS RAPED,
有没有可能SHELLY被强奸了
AND THAT LED TO HER SUICIDE?
然后导致了她的自杀?
NO, IT'S NOT.
不可能 不是的
DID SHELLY HAVE ANY HISTORY OF DEPRESSION?
SHELLY有抑郁症吗?
SHE PUT A LOT OF PRESSURE ON HERSELF.
她给自己很大的压力
SHE GOT A'S,
她考试拿As
VOLUNTEERED WITH THE YOUTH GROUP,
青年团体的志愿者
PLAYED VARSITY VOLLEYBALL IN HIGH SCHOOL,
在中学参加了大学排球代表队
BUT SHE ALWAYS HANDLED IT WITH GRACE.
但是她始终依赖神恩处理压力问题
DID SHE LEAVE A NOTE?
她有留下字条吗?
AND IF SO, WOULD IT BE POSSIBLE FOR US TO TAKE IT AND ANALYZE IT?
如果有的话 我们能拿去做分析吗?
THERE WASN'T A NOTE.
那不是字条
WE WILL RETURN IT AND WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
我们会归还并给予你们应得的尊重
THIS ISN'T SOMETHING THAT I'M ASKING LIGHTLY.
这不是我随便问问的事
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT TO YOU, YOU WALK INTO MY HOME,
给予你们应得的尊重 你们来我家
YOU ASK IF MY DAUGHTER, WHO WE BURIED 2 MONTHS AGO,
询问我们两个月前失去的女儿
WAS ALSO SEXUALLY VIOLATED.
是不是给性侵犯了?
I'M SORRY.
对不起
I HAVE A LITTLE GIRL AND I CAN'T SAY HOW I'D REACT
我有个小女儿 而且我说不出如果她
IF SOMETHING HAPPENED TO HER,
发生了什么事时有什么反应
BUT I WOULD LIKE TO BELIEVE THAT I WOULD DO WHATEVER
但我更愿意相信 我会做那些该做的
WAS NECESSARY TO MAKE SURE THAT NO OTHER FAMILY WENT THROUGH THAT SAME PAIN.
以确保别的家庭不用再经受同样的痛苦
I'D LIKE TO GO LIE DOWN.
我想睡一会
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
谢谢拨空见面
I'LL SEE YOU OUT.
我会再和你见面的
I LOVE MY WIFE.
我爱我妻子
I'M SURE YOU DO.
我相信你是的
SHE WAS RAPED.
她被强奸了
THE UNSUB GOT HER PREGNANT.
疑犯让她怀了孕
"I'M CHOOSING THE SIN OF SUICIDE OVER THE SIN OF ABORTION,
我选择自杀的罪孽取代堕胎的罪孽
"BECAUSE I CAN'T BRING HIS BABY INTO THE WORLD.
因为我不能把他的孩子带到人世来
PLEASE DON'T HATE ME, SHELLY."
请不要恨我 SHELLY
THE ATTACKS AT THE COLLEGE STOPPED TWO MONTHS AGO,
学院里的袭击两个月前停止了
RIGHT AFTER SHELLY'S SUICIDE.
刚好在SHELLY自杀后
THAT HAD HAVE BEEN THE STRESSOR.
应该就是这个刺激了他
HE THINKS OF THESE AS RELATIONSHIPS.
他认为这是亲密关系
IN HIS MIND SHELLY KILLED THEIR BABY.
在他心里 SHELLY杀了他们的婴儿
JASON, HOTCH.
JASON 我是HOTCH
WE NEED TO GO BACK TO THE LAST VICTIM AND ASK ONE MORE QUESTION.
我们得去问最后那个受害者一个问题
DID HE SAY ANYTHING TO YOU ABOUT CHILDREN, FAMILY?
他跟你说起过孩子 家庭吗?
NO.
没有
DID HE MENTION ANYTHING ABOUT SUICIDE?
他提到过关于自杀的事吗?
REFER TO A PERSONAL TRAGEDY,
归结于个人悲剧
SOMEBODY HE WAS MAYBE IN A RELATIONSHIP WITH?
是一个跟他有亲密关系的人?
WHY ARE YOU ASKING ME THIS?
你干吗问我这些?
ONE OF THE VICTIMS TOOK HER OWN LIFE
有个受害者发现
WHEN SHE REALIZED THE RAPIST GOT HER PREGNANT.
强奸犯让她怀孕后自杀了
WHAT IS IT?
怎么了?
I'M TRYING TO HAVE A BABY.
我想要个孩子
FOR HOW LONG?
多久了?
I HAD AN APPOINTMENT AT THE CLINIC
被袭击前几天 我在诊所那里
TO TALK ABOUT INSEMINATION A FEW DAYS BEFORE I WAS ATTACKED.
预约了谈人工授精的事
DID ANYONE ELSE KNOW ABOUT THAT?
还有别人知道么?
I JUST DECIDED.
我刚下的决定
I'M 38.
我38岁了
I FIGURED I COULDN'T AFFORD TO JUST WAIT AROUND
我确信自己等不及
FOR THE RIGHT MAN TO SHOW UP.
合适的男人出现了
HEY.
嘿
I TALKED THE OTHER 2 VICTIMS IN THEIR 30s.
我跟其中两个30几岁的被害人谈过
THEY HAD BOTH GONE TO A FERTILITY CLINIC
她们都在被袭击前5天里
WITHIN 5 DAYS OF THEIR ATTACK.
去了同个妇产科诊所
SAME ONE EACH TIME? YEP.
-每次都同一个? -没错
HAVE GARCIA RUN DOWN EMPLOYMENT RECORDS.
GARCIA浏览雇员记录了吗?
THEY MIGHT BE LOOKING AT SOMEONE WHO WORKS THERE
他们应该找那些在那工作
OR WHO HAS ACCESS TO THEIR MEDICAL RECORDS.
或是得到过她们病历的人
YOU GOT IT.
好的
WHAT'S THE SIGNIFICANCE OF THE 5 DAYS?
那五天有什么重要意义?
THE MOST POPULAR FERTILITY DRUG IS CLOMIPHENE,
最常用的助孕药是舒经酚
AND THE CLINIC WOULD MOST LIKELY HAVE A POLICY
诊所大概会有规定
NOT TO ATTEMPT INSEMINATION UNTIL THE DRUG REGIMEN IS COMPLETE.
在该疗程完成之前不去试图授精
SO THEN GETTING THERE BEFORE THEY BEGIN THE INSEMINATION PROCESS
所以选在被害人开始授精前进行犯罪
WOULD GUARANTEE THE UNSUB PATERNITY.
可以保证她们怀上他的孩子
HE'S TRYING TO GET THEM PREGNANT.
他想让她们怀孕
HE HASN'T CHANGED HIS FANTASY,
他没有改变他的幻想
HE'S MERELY FOUND A WAY TO PERFECT IT.
不过是找到了让它变完美的方法
WELL, THAT EXPLAINS A CHANGE IN VICTIMOLOGY.
这解释了受害者模式的改变
HE'S TARGETED YOUNG, ULTRA-RELIGIOUS GIRLS,
他选择了那些极端虔诚的年轻女孩
WHO HE ASSUMED WOULDN'T WANT TO HAVE AN ABORTION.
她们绝对不会去堕胎
SO WHEN SHELLY KILLED HERSELF,
所以当SHELLY自杀的时候
HE DECIDED CHANGE IT UP AND GO AFTER WOMEN WHO WERE DESPERATE TO HAVE A BABY.
他决定改变目标转向那些渴望怀孕的妇女
THE UNSUB KNEW SHELLY NORVELL WAS PREGNANT,
疑犯知道SHELLY NORVELL怀孕了
MEANS HE'S STILL WATCHING HIS PAST VICTIMS.
意味着他还在盯着以前的受害者
ELLE, TALK TO CALLAHAN,
ELLE 跟CALLAHAN说
TELL THEM WE NEED PATROLS MONITORING EVERYONE ON THAT VICTIM LIST.
我们需要巡警监控每一个名单上的受害者
GOT IT.
收到
YOU EVER SEEN ANYTHING LIKE THIS BEFORE?
你以前碰过类似的事情吗?
GARY HEIDNICK IN PHILADELPHIA.
费城 GARY HEIDNICK
HE KEPT WOMEN IN A DUNGEON PRISON FOR YEARS
他把受害人关在地牢数年
WITH THE HOPES OF IMPREGNATING THEM.
为使她们怀孕
HEIDNICK WAS A SEXUAL SADIST.
HEIDNICK是个性虐待狂
HE TORTURED THE WOMEN
他拷打了这些妇女
AND EVEN ENDED UP EATING ONE OF THEM.
甚至最后还把其中一个给吃了
THIS IS A POWER REASSURANCE RAPIST.
这是权利重认型强奸犯
SO IN THIS GUY'S TWISTED MIND, THESE ARE LOVE STORIES?
在那家伙扭曲的心灵里 这还是爱情故事咯?
OF COURSE, THEY ARE.
当然啦 她们都是
HE'S STARTING FAMILIES.
他开始构建家庭了
I'M SORRY, BUT WHOEVER'S COMMITTING THESE CRIMES
抱歉 任何跟那些罪案有关系的人
COULDN'T WORK AT THIS CLINIC.
不可能在这诊所上班
iN I'M THE ONLY MAN HERE.
我是这里唯一的男性
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN THERE ISN'T A CONNECTION.
但这并不意味跟这里没有关联
WE NEED YOUR HELP TO FIGURE OUT WHAT IT MIGHT BE.
我们需要你帮助确认有什么关联
COULD YOU EXCUSE ME, JUST A MINUTE?
稍等好吗?
CAN YOU JUST FILL THAT OUT?
你可以把表填一下吗?
THAT'S GREAT. JUST RIGHT THERE.
太好了 就在那边填吧
LOOK, WHAT'S HAPPENING IS JUST HORRIBLE,
你看 发生的事情是很可怕
BUT THE MARGINS ON THE CLINIC LIKE THIS ARE INCREDIBLY SLIM.
但象我们这样的诊所 利润是非常微薄的
AND IF WORD GETS OUT THERE'S A CONNECTION TO THIS RAPIST,
而且如果有人提起我们跟强奸犯有关联
MY PRACTICE WOULD BE RUINED.
我的实验科目会被毁掉的
TO BE HONEST I DON'T CARE ABOUT YOUR PRACTICE.
说实在的我对你的实验不感冒
3 WOMEN WERE RAPED AFTER COMING HERE.
有3个妇女来这后被强奸了
THAT'S NOT A COINCIDENCE. IT'S A PATTERN.
那不是偶合 已经是种模式了
IF YOU'RE IMPLYING THAT I COULD BE A SUSPECT.
如果你在暗示我可能是嫌疑犯
I SHOULD LET YOU KNOW THAT I HAD A VASECTOMY 25 YEARS AGO.
我可以告诉你 25年前我就结扎了
WE JUST WANT TO KNOW IF THERE'S ANYONE
我们就想知道在这诊所
IN AND OUT OF THIS CLINIC WHO FITS THE PROFILE.
进进出出的人里面 有谁跟侧写材料相符
QUIET, LIVES ALONE, AWKWARD WITH WOMEN,
不爱说话 独居 不擅于跟女人接触
YET HANGS AROUND THE OFFICE
还有长时间呆在这里
A LITTLE TOO LONG JUST TO BE NEAR THEM.
以便接近那些受害者
NO, IT'S JUST A SMALL CLINIC.
不可能 这是个小诊所
I ONLY HIRE WOMEN.
我只雇用女员工
MY PATIENTS ARE JUST MUCH MORE COMFORTABLE AROUND THEM.
我的病人在她们身边才会感觉自在
WHAT ABOUT ELSEWHERE, COMPUTER SUPPORT, JANITOR?
外来的呢 电脑维护的 清洁员?
MY DAUGHTER HANDLES ALL OF THE TECHNICAL BUSINESS
我女儿负责处理所有的技术问题
AND I HAVE A CLEANING CREW OF TWO WOMEN.
而且我有两名妇女组成的清洁队
SORRY.
不好意思了
WHAT IS THAT, DOCTOR?
医生 那是什么?
IT'S JUST A QUESTIONNAIRE
问卷而已
WE HAND OUT TO LEARN MORE ABOUT OUR CLIENT BASE.
我们分发出去 用于了解病人的基本资料
THIS IS EVERYTHING THE UNSUB KNEW ABOUT THE VICTIMS.
疑犯掌握的关于受害者资料就是在这得到的
WHO ELSE SEES THESE?
还有谁看过这些?
I DON'T COMPROMISE THE MEDICAL PRIVACY OF MY PATIENTS.
我不会泄露我病人的医疗隐私的
WELL, I SELL THE FORMS TO A DIRECT MARKETING COMPANY
嗯 我把这些调查表卖给了一家直销公司
CALLED FIRST HAND MEDIA.
叫做第一手传媒
THEY JUST TARGET BUYING HABITS.
他们目标是购买习惯
NO MEDICAL INFORMATION CHANGES HANDS.
没有医疗信息被转手
IT'S NOT ILLEGAL.
这可不违法
YEAH, BUT THE MARGINS ON A PLACE LIKE THIS,
是的 但象你们这样赚钱
WORD GETS OUT, YOUR PRACTICE WOULD BE RUINED.
说出去的话 你的实验科目可是会毁掉的哦
DAYTON, OHIO. YOU'RE ON THE AIR.
OHIO州 DAYTON 电台连线上了
I'D LIKE TO MAKE A REQUEST.
我有个不情之请
WITH THAT SULTRY VOICE?
怎么跟我说话的?
YOU NAME IT.
你给我说说看
ALL RIGHT, LISTEN,
好啦 听着
IT'S A MARKETING FIRM BY THE NAME OF FIRST HAND MEDIA.
一个叫第一手媒体的市场公司
I WANT YOU TO SEE IF THEY HAVE ANY CONNECTION
我要你看看他们跟第一批受害者
TO THE COLLEGES FROM THE FIRST SET OF VICTIMS.
所在的学院有什么关联
BEHOLD, FIRST HAND MEDIA PROCESSES
瞧 第一手媒体公司处理了
ALL THE FRESHMAN ORIENTATION QUESTIONNAIRES.
所有新生的定位调查问卷
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
太棒了
OH, ONE LAST FAVOR.
噢 再帮你个忙
LOOK UP THE WORDS SEXY AND BRILLIANT
在你的电脑里检索
IN THAT COMPUTER OF YOURS AND TELL ME WHAT YOU COME UP WITH.
性感跟才华横溢 看看出来什么
LOOK AT THAT, IT'S ME.
看到啦 就是我
YOU ARE A GODDESS WOMAN, CIAO.
你是天神般的女人 再见了
IT WAS A...
这是个
IT WAS A WORK CALL.
业务电话
YOU REALLY THINK THIS RAPIST IS ONE OF MY GUYS?
你们真的认为强奸犯是我们的人?
WELL, HE'S USED TO BEING IN STRANGERS' HOMES, ALWAYS ON THE PHONE.
是这样的 他经常呆在陌生人的家里 始终使用电话
THAT'S HOW HE'S CONFIDENT.
那是为什么他会自信的原因
THANKS TO YOUR RESEARCH, HE FEELS LIKE HE KNOWS THESE WOMEN.
托调研的福 他自我感觉认识这些女人
CREATE A LIST OF ANY EMPLOYEES YOU HAVE
把你所有负责妇科诊所跟大学的
THAT WORKED IN A FERTILITY CLINIC AND UNIVERSITY QUTIONNAIRES.
调查问卷工作的雇员列个名单
I GIVE EVERY EMPLOYEE COMPLETE ACCESS TO ALL OF OUR MATERIALS.
我给了每个员工所有资料的使用权限
IT HELPS KEEP THEM FRESH IF THEY CAN ALTERNATE BETWEEN TYPES OF CALLS.
如果他们能交替电话和录入 有助于资料的不断更新
SO I FILL OUT MY INTIMATE PERSONAL INFORMATION
那么说我填好了隐私信息
AND THEN YOU JUST SHARE IT WITH EVERYONE
你就拿去给那些
YOU HAVE WORKING HERE FOR MINIMUM WAGE?
靠最低工资生活的手下分享了?
I SENSE AN ATTITUDE.
我是有原则的
WE NEED COPIES OF EVERY SINGLE QUESTIONNAIRE
我们要你在诊所里拿到的
THAT YOU GOT FROM THE CLINIC.
每一份问卷的副本
WE CAN GET A WARRANT HERE IN ABOUT AN HOUR IF YOU PREFER.
如果你喜欢的话 我们可以在一小时内拿到许可证
LOOK, IF YOU THINK ABOUT IT,
你想想看
ALL I'M DOING IS PROFILING, JUST LIKE YOU GUYS.
我做的一切也算是侧写 跟你们一样
LET'S NOT THINK ABOUT IT.
那就别想
ALL THESE?
这些都要?
WE COVER THE ENTIRE GREAT LAKES REGION.
我们可是覆盖了整个大湖区哦
LET'S NARROW IT DOWN.
我们来收窄一下
THE GUY WE'RE LOOKING FOR IS A MALE, WHITE,
我们找的这家伙是男性 白人
BETWEEN THE AGES OF 20 AND 40,
20到40岁之间
SOCIALLY AWKWARD, UNABLE TO MAKE--
不擅长社交
CONNECTIONS EASILY.
不轻易跟人联系
I HAVE 250 EMPLOYEES.
我有250名员工
MOST OF THOSE ARE MEN
大多数是男的
AND EVERY SINGLE ONE OF THEM MATCH
每个单身员工都符合
THE DESCRIPTION YOU JUST GAVE ME.
你刚跟我描述的
WOW. I HEARD YOU RAN INTO A WALL OF PAPER.
哇 我听说你陷入文山中了
YOU CAN LOCK YOUR DOORS, BUT THESE PEOPLE STILL FIND A WAY INTO YOUR HOME.
你可以把门锁上 但这些家伙还是能进入你家
ELLE, IT MIGHT BE WORTH GOING BACK TO THE VICTIMS.
ELLE  再去找那些受害者应该会有点用
IT'S A LONG SHOT, BUT MAYBE SOMEBODY REMEMBERS
很耗时间 但或许有人会记得
A FIRST NAME FROM A TELEMARKETING CALL.
电话市场调查那个人的名字
YEAH, THE UNSUB FEELS A CONNECTION WITH THEM.
没错 疑犯觉得自己跟她们有关系
SO HE WOULDN'T LIE OR USE AN ALIAS.
那么他就不会撒慌或者使用化名
WE KNOW THIS GUY'S DNA IS NOT IN THE SYSTEM,
我们知道那家伙的DNA不在比对系统里
BUT I'LL CROSS-CHECK EMPLOYMENT RECORDS
但我会交叉检查那些雇员
AGAINST SEXUAL MISDEMEANORS: PEEPING, EXPOSURE.
轻型性犯罪 偷窥 露体的记录
GOOD.
干得好
SEPARATE DATA FORMS FROM THE REST OF THE REGION.
把这区域剩下的数据表分开
SO, WHAT DO WE KNOW FROM THE LATEST SET OF VICTIMS?
我们从最后一批受害者那得到什么了?
THEY'RE ALL SINGLE AND ALL OVER 35.
她们都单身而且年过35
EACH OF THEM ALSO INDICATED RECENTLY BUYING BOOKS
还都在最近买了
ON BABIES AND CHILDBEARING.
婴儿跟分娩方面的书
SO HE KNOWS THEY'RE COMMITTED TO HAVING CHILDREN,
所以他知道她们很想有孩子
WHICH MEANS THEY'RE MUCH LESS LIKELY TO ABORT,
这意味着她们不会去中止怀孕
EVEN IN THE CASE OF RAPE.
即便是被强奸得来的
GET THIS, EACH OF THE VICTIMS ALSO CHECKED
看看 在问到可否
THE YES BOX WHEN ASKED IF IT WOULD BE OK TO CONTACT THEM
因儿科物品的特殊交易与她们联系时
ON SPECIAL DEALS ON PEDIATRIC ITEMS.
每个受害者都勾选了可以
IN THE UNSUB'S MIND THEY'VE CONSENTED.
在疑犯的心里面她们就是认可了
HE THINKS HE'S DOING THEM A SERVICE.
他认为他是在为她们服务
CHECK THOSE FORMS FOR EACH OF THOSE ELEMENTS.
在那些表格中查找这些要素
IF WE CAN NARROW IT DOWN TO A POTENTIAL LIST OF VICTIMS
如果我们能够收窄出一张潜在受害者的名单
WE CAN BE WAITING FOR HIM.
就可以守株待兔了
ANY HITS?
有发现没?
GOT ONE. REID?
-有一个 -REID呢?
NOTHING.
没发现
IT'S THE ONLY ONE?
就只有这一个?
IT'S A SMALL CITY.
这是个小地方
THERE CAN'T BE VERY MANY SINGLE WOMEN
不可能有很多单身
IN THEIR LATE 30s GOING TO THE EXACT SAME FERTILITY CLINIC.
30多岁妇女去同一家妇科诊所的
SO, WE KNOW WHO HE'S GOING AFTER NEXT.
我们知道他下一个目标了
???????
警察
??????????????
有人在家吗?
THERE WAS NO FORCED ENTRY.
没有硬闯的痕迹
WE'RE STILL NOT SURE HOW HE GOT IN.
我们还是不能确定他是怎么进去的
M.O.'S THE SAME? NO.
相同手法? 对
I'M GOING TO TAKE A LOOK INSIDE.
我得进去看看
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOUR MEN DOING?
你的人吃干饭的啊?
EXCUSE ME?
什么意思?
WELL, YOU CAN HAVE MEN OUTSIDE THE DOOR,
你的人就在门外
BUT A WOMAN CAN STILL GET RAPED INSIDE.
那女人还是在屋里被强奸了
THEY KNOCKED, THERE WAS NO ANSWER,
他们敲了门 没人应答
THERE WAS NO LEGAL CAUSE TO ENTER.
就这么进去是不合法的
SO, THEY JUST WALKED AWAY?
那么他们就走了?
NO, THEY LEFT MESSAGES THAT IT WAS URGENT
没有 他们留了口信
SHE CONTACT THE POLICE.
如果有急事 叫她报警
WHICH MUST BE ON THE MACHINE
肯定在那家伙
RIGHT AFTER THAT CREEP LEFT A MESSAGE
留了口信说要去
SAYING HE WAS GOING TO RAPE HER.
强奸她之后
THEY DID EVERYTHING IN THEIR POWER.
他们尽力了
YOU JUST KEEP TELLING YOURSELF THAT.
说给自己听去吧
ELLE.
ELLE
EXCUSE ME. HOW BAD WERE HER INJURIES?
不好意思 她的伤有多重?
SHE'S LUCKY. THEY'RE RELATIVELY MINOR.
她运气好 它们都比较轻微
DO ME A FAVOR, DON'T TELL HER THAT SHE'S LUCKY.
帮帮忙 别跟她说她运气好
THERE'S NOT A POTENTIAL VICTIM IN THE QUESTIONNAIRES.
调查问卷上没有潜在的受害者了
WHO KNOWS WHEN WE'RE GOING TO GET ANOTR SHOT AT HIM.
鬼知道什么时候我们还能再盯到他
THE NOOSE IS TIGHTENING.
我们的网已经越收越小
YOU SAW THAT STACK OF FORMS.
那看那堆表格
THIS COMPANY HANDLES THE ENTIRE GREAT LAKES REGION.
这公司处理整个大湖区的业务
IF HE THINKS WE'RE CLOSE, HE CAN TAKE OFF
如果他觉得我们结案了
AND HE'S GOT A WHOLE NEW LIST OF VICTIMS IN ANOTHER CITY.
他会去别的城市再列出全新的受害者清单
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
你怎么想呢?
WHAT HE STARTED WITH COLLEGE STUDENTS, HE RAPED ONE A WEEK.
他开始是怎么对付那些女生的 一星期强奸一个
NOW, HE HAS TO WAIT FOR THE RIGHT SET OF CIRCUMSTANCES,
现在他在等待适合的环境
BUT HE WANTS MORE VICTIMS.
但他需要更多的受害者
LET'S GIVE HIM ONE.
那我们就给他一个
YOU THINK ELLE'S READY FOR IT?
你认为ELLE能干这活了?
WE'LL BE THERE FOR HER.
我们会在那跟着她的
WHAT'S MY STORY?
我的经历?
YOU'RE A LEGAL SECRETARY, 36, DIVORCED.
你是个法律助理 36岁 失婚
BACK THERE, THE QUESTIONNAIRE'S 2 DAYS.
话说回来 调查问卷要两天
SO IN THE UNSUB'S MIND HE'S ALREADY BEHIND HIS NORMAL SCHEDULE.
疑犯会觉得已经回到正常的日程上
THIS GUY'S ITCHING FOR ANOTHER VICTIM, THOUGH.
那家伙渴望有个新猎物
ONCE HE SEES THAT FORM HE'S GOING TO WANT TO STAKE YOU OUT.
只要他看到那张表 就会想去监视你
YOU NEED TO LET HIM SEE YOU.
你得让他看到你
HE WANTS TO KNOW WHEN YOU LEAVE,
他想知道你什么时候离家
WHEN YOU COME HOME, WHEN YOU HAVE FRIENDS OVER.
什么时候回家 什么时候会朋友
HE BREAKS INTO THESE HOUSES WHEN THE WOMEN ARE AWAY.
他在那些女人离家时闯进她们的房子
SO, HE NEEDS TO SEE YOU LEAVE.
所以他得看到你离开家
ALL WE NEED TO DO IS GET HIM TO BREACH THAT DOOR.
我们要的是让他破门而入
ONCE WE GOT HIM ON BREAKING AND ENTERING,
只要我们揪到他一次
WE GOT REASON TO GET DNA AND HIS ASS IS OURS.
我们就有理由取DNA样本 他就任我们宰割了
ANOTHER THING, DON'T GO OUT WITH YOUR GUN.
还有件事 别带枪出门
IT'S TOO RISKY.
太冒险了
IF HE SEES IT, WE MIGHT LOSE HIM.
如果他看到枪 就抓不到他了
KEEP IT SOMEPLACE INSIDE SO YOU CAN GET TO IT EASILY.
把它放在房子里最容易拿到的地方
I'M GOING TO BE RIGHT OUT FRONT,
我就在房子前面
HOTCH AND GIDEON WILL BE AROUND THE CORNER IN THE SURVEILLANCE VAN.
HOTCH和GIDEON会呆在拐角的监视车里
AND, DON'T FORGET YOU'RE WIRED,
然后 别忘了你身上有对讲机
SO WE'LL BE WITH YOU AT ALL TIMES.
我们会全程跟你在一起
HEY, YOU GOOD?
嘿 还好吧?
I'M GOOD.
没事
SHE'S IN.
她进去了
WHY ISN'T SHE LEAVING?
为什么还不离开呢?
SHE NEEDS TO GET OUT OF THERE.
她必须从那出来
WHAT IS THAT?
那是什么?
MORGAN, CALL HER.
MORGAN 打电话给她
COME ON, PICK UP. PICK UP.
快点接啊
I THINK WE MIGHT HAVE COMPANY.
我想有人来了
TALK TO ME, TIGER.
说话 猛男
GARCIA, I NEED YOU TO RUN A PLATE FOR ME.
GARCIA 帮我查副车牌
??????????????????????
P M 6 8 Y 3
WILLIAM LEE, 10308 PINEHURST AVENUE.
WILLIAM LEE PINEHURST大道10308号
OK, CAN YOU GIVE ME WHERE HE WORKS?
好的 能查出他在哪上班吗?
FEEL MY SPEED.
够快吧
HE WORKS FOR FIRST HAND MEDIA.
他在第一手传媒工作
ALL RIGHT, I GOT IT. THANKS.
知道了 谢谢
IT'S HIM.
就是他
BINGO.
没错
ALPHA, BRAVO, SHE'S ON THE MOVE.
一组 二组 她出发了
WHAT'S SHE DOING WITH HER GUN OUT?
她干吗带枪出门啊?
JUST GET IN THE CAR.
快上车
DON'T LET HIM KNOW THAT YOU SEE HIM.
别让他知道你看见他了
WHAT THE HELL IS SHE DOING? EASY, BABY.
她要干吗? 别冲动
SHE'S PANICKING. EASY, EASY.
她有点慌张 冷静 冷静
COME ON, ELLE. BACK OFF.
快点 ELLE 退回去
BACK OFF. WE'VE GOT NO REASON TO BRINHIM IN.
退回去 我们没有理由抓他
DON'T BLOW IT, DON'T BLOW IT.
不要搞砸了 不要搞砸了
GO, GO, GO! EVERYBODY, GO.
上 上 上 大家上
FBI, PUT YOUR HANDS WHERE I CAN SEE THEM.
FBI 把手放在我看得到的地方
GET OUT OF THE CAR!
下车
??????/ ???????
马上 趴地上去
PUT YOUR PALMS UP!
掌心朝上
SHUT UP!
闭嘴
I WAS JUST STOPPING TO LOOK AT MY MAP.
我只是停下来 查查地图
YOU GOT NO REASON TO KEEP ME HERE.
你没有理由留我在这
WE KNOW YOU WORK AT FIRST HAND MEDIA
我们知道你在第一手传媒工作
AND YOU HAD ACCESS TO INFORMATION ABOUT ALL THESE WOMEN.
而且你有权限查看这些女人的资料
BUT I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING WRONG.
我没做错事啊
WE KNOW THAT.
我们知道
I APOLOGIZE.
我向你道歉
WE KNOW HOW MUCH YOU CARE ABOUT THESE WOMEN.
我们知道你有多关心这些女人
YOU DO CARE ABOUT THEM, DON'T YOU?
你真的关心她们对吧?
HE'S 28 YEARS OLD AND HAS A HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA,
他今年28岁 中学文凭
BUT HE'S HAD 12 JOBS IN THE PAST 10 YEARS.
但在过去10年里换了12份工作
HOME LIFE?
家庭情况?
HE LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER UNTIL SHE WAS DIAGNOSED
他跟他母亲同住
WITH PANCREATIC CANCER 6 MONTHS AGO.
直到6个月前她诊断出患有胰腺癌
ONE LAST CHANCE TO MAKE MAMA PROUD, BY STARTING A FAMILY.
唯一最后的机会让他母亲感到骄傲 就是成家
HOW ARE THEY PLAYING IT?
他们要怎么办?
DEEP EMPATHY.
深度同情
SMART.
聪明
YEAH. WELL, IT BETTER WORK.
是的 最好能奏效
IF THEY DON'T GET HIM TO CONFESS,
如果他们不能让他坦白
WE GOT NO REASON TO HOLD HIM.
我们没理由再留置他
WE KNOW THAT DATING THOSE YOUNGER GIRLS WAS A MISTAKE.
我们知道跟年轻姑娘约会是个错误
THEY WERE JUST TOO IMMATURE.
她们太不成熟了
OLDER ONES ARE--
年长些的
THEY'RE LOOKING TO START FAMILIES.
她们想成家
THEY'RE EVEN WILLING TO SHELL OUT A LOT OF MONEY JUST TO HAVE KIDS.
她们甚至愿意为了有个孩子花一大笔钱
LET'S JUST SAY THAT THAT'S TRUE,
我们得说这是真的
THEN WHOEVER WOULD HAVE BEEN WITH THEM
不管谁跟她们在一起
WOULD'VE BEEN HELPING.
都会有帮助的
THAT'S WHAT WE WERE SAYING.
这就是我们要谈的
YOU'RE THE BEST THING THAT'S EVER HAPPENED TO THEM.
你就是她们遇见最好的人选了
WHO'S THIS?
这是谁?
NO, NO, NO, NO.
不 不不不
SON OF A BITCH.
真混蛋
WHY DON'T YOU VOLUNTEER A DNA SAMPLE?
为什么不主动提供DNA样本呢?
IF YOU'RE THE KID,
如果你是那小孩
WOULDN'T YOU WANT TO KNOW WHO YOUR FATHER WAS?
你不想去知道谁是你爸爸吗?
DON'T SAY ANOTHER WORD.
不用再说了
THIS IS OVER.
一切都结束了
I'M ADVISING MY CLIENT NOT TO ANSWER ANY MORE QUESTIONS.
我建议我的当事人不要再回答任何问题
I'M ASSUMING THAT WE'RE FREE TO GO.
我觉得我们随时可以走
YOU'RE LETTING HIM WALK?
你让他走?
BACK OFF, ELLE.
走开 ELLE
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT HE'S DONE.
你都不知道他干了些什么
THE ONLY REASON HE'S WALKING IS BECAUSE YOU PANICKED.
他可以开罪的唯一原因就是你的惊慌
I'M SUPPOSED TO BELIEVE THAT YOU'VE GOT MY BACK?
活该我就得相信你们会支援我?
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING TO ME?
你在说什么呢?
THE LAST TIME YOU SENT ME HOME HOTCH IT GOT ME SHOT.
上一次你送我回家 我被枪击了
WALK WITH ME, RIGHT NOW.
跟我走 赶紧
YOU NEED TO GET SOME AIR.
你得透下气冷静一下
WHILE YOU DO, I WANT YOU TO THINK ABOUT THIS JOB,
你要做什么时 我希望你想想这份工作
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH, WHAT YOU'RE CAPABLE OF.
你是怎么通过的 是怎么被认可的
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
你懂我意思吗?
SO, WHAT HAPPENS NOW?
那现在该怎么办?
DO YOU STAY?
你会留下来吗?
YOU HAVE YOUR MAN, YOU JUST HAVE TO WAIT FOR HIM TO SLIP UP.
你有你的人 你等着他犯错就行了
YOU SAID YOURSELF,
你说什么呢
HE HAS ACCESS TO INFORMATION ON WOMEN FOR AN 8-STATE REGION.
他现在能查到8个州妇女的资料
LOOK, YOU'RE A GOOD COP, MY MONEY'S ON YOU.
你是个好警察 你行的
GET SOME REST, MY FRIEND.
休息休息吧
WHEEL'S UP TOMORROW AT NOON.
明天中午启程
IS THIS WHAT YOU DO?
你就是这么做的?
YOU WAIT FOR THEM UNTIL THEY GET HOME?
你等着她们回家?
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO BE HERE.
你不应该在这儿的
WHAT, YOU CAN'T TALK TO A WOMAN WITHOUT A GUN IN YOU HAND?
什么呀 你手里没枪就不敢跟女人说话了?
YOU AND I BOTH KNOW WHAT YOU ARE
你我都知道你是什么东西
AND YOU'RE NOT GOING TO HURT WOMEN ANYMORE.
你再也伤害不了女人了
I WOULD NEVER HURT THEM, YOU KNOW THAT.
你知道我永远都不会伤害她们的
ds THAT'S WHY YOU LET ME GO.
这就是你会让我走的原因吧?
I DIDN'T LET YOU DO ANYTHING.
我可没让你干吗
YOU'RE VERY PRETTY.
你很漂亮
WHAT DID YOU JUST SAY TO ME?
你刚跟我说啥了?
WHY DO YOU CHOOSE TO DO A JOB THAT IS SO DANGEROUS?
为什么你选了这么一份危险的职业?
YOU SHOULD FIND A MAN TO TAKE CARE OF YOU.
你该找个男人照顾你
OH, LIKE YOU TOOK CARE OF THOSE WOMEN?
噢 象你照顾那些女人一样?
NOW YOU'RE TRYING TO INTERROGATE ME.
现在你是在审问我
YOU KNOW YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO DO THAT.
你知道你不能这么做的
I'M JUST HERE TO LET YOU KNOW THAT
我在这儿是要你知道
I'M NOT GOING TO REST UNTIL YOU GO AWAY.
不除掉你我是不会休息的
YOU'RE HERE BECAUSE YOU WANT ME TO SAY THANK YOU.
你在这儿是要我跟你说声谢谢
YOU'RE SICK.
你真病态
REALLY?
真的吗?
BECAUSE...
因为
WITHOUT YOU I WOULD STILL BE LOCKED UP.
没有你我现在还在牢里呢
I DIDN'T LET YOU WALK.
我没让你走
THANK YOU.
谢了
YOU'VE MADE A LOT OF WOMEN VERY HAPPY.
你让很多女人非常开心
HEY, LEE.
嘿 LEE
WHAT HAPPENED?
发生什么事?
I WAS HAVING A CONVERSATION WITH HIM
我跟他在交谈
AND HE DREW HIS WEAPON AND I FIRED.
然后他拔了枪 我就开火了
YOU ALL RIGHT?
你没事吧?
??????????
没事 谢谢
CAN'T LET YOU SPEAK TO HER
程序完结前
UNTIL SHE'S BEEN PROCESSED.
你们不能和她说话
PROCEDURE.
手续问题
WHAT HAPPENED?
发生什么事了?
SHE CAME TO STAKE HIS PLACE OUT,
她要去监视他的住所
HE SAW HER, HE HAD A GUN.
他看到她 他身上有枪
DON'T WORRY, IT'S CUT AND DRY. SELF-DEFENSE.
别担心 毫无疑问 是自卫
SHE'LL HAVE HER BADGE BACK BY TOMORROW.
她明天就能恢复原职
THANK YOU.
谢谢